<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Capitalism on Kwon.nyc</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/capitalism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Capitalism on Kwon.nyc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 09:01:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/capitalism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Radicalized by a soap dispenser</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/radicalized-by-a-soap-dispenser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 09:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/radicalized-by-a-soap-dispenser/</guid>
      <description>I get frustrated when things don&amp;rsquo;t work.
Increasingly I have been getting especially frustrated when things that are fancy don&amp;rsquo;t work, because I feel bamboozled.
The other day, I went to wash my hands in the bathroom at work, and the automated soap dispenser/foamer didn&amp;rsquo;t work. I was awkwardly placing and retracting my hands under the sensor repeatedly like please sir&amp;hellip; just a bit of soap to wash my bathroom hands&amp;hellip; and nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net positive, maybe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/net-positive-maybe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 11:02:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/net-positive-maybe/</guid>
      <description>This is a half-baked thought I&amp;rsquo;ve been preheating for a bit.
Technology has changed the way we consume and create media, and considering all the benefits against the drawbacks, sometimes it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like a net improvement to me. Or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just that things evolved too quickly, we got excited about all the upside and didn&amp;rsquo;t think enough about second and third order effects, and now we&amp;rsquo;re still figuring out a way to catch up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimize</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/optimize/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 23:06:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/optimize/</guid>
      <description>After I quit medicine and went corporate (as corporate as tech startups can be, which I guess depends on your vantage point; for me it was and is extremely corporate coming from doctoring), I got really into it and became particularly fascinated to learn how business leaders operate and spend their time (at work and in life) in order to be the most efficient and effective they can be. I guess a lot of people who came up in corporate work (and maybe the culture at large which is often dictated by creatives who may pooh-pooh the corporate life) think MASSIVE EYEROLL when they hear what the latest tech bro thinkboi has to say about optimizing their life and their time, but I actually found it pretty refreshing that in business a spade is called a spade and that spade is a dollar and nobody pretends that we aren&amp;rsquo;t trying to make money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital noise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 09:30:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/noise/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m getting worn down by all the digital noise. By digital noise I mean the constant barrage of alerts, notifications, pings, email subscriptions I didn&amp;rsquo;t sign up for, email subscriptions I DID sign up for but regret doing so, all the inputs that come through my connected devices.
Sometimes I secretly wish I could be one of those people who moves off the grid, abandons the smartphone, deletes all social media, and lives a quiet minimalist life in the woods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
