<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>End of Year on Kwon.nyc</title>
    <link>https://kwon.nyc/tags/end-of-year/</link>
    <description>Recent content in End of Year on Kwon.nyc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 09:40:41 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kwon.nyc/tags/end-of-year/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2022 in review, part 2</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 09:40:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&#34;https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022/&#34;&gt;promised&lt;/a&gt;, here&amp;rsquo;s the second part of my year in review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To recap: I audited where I spent my time (loosely) and where I spent my money (incredibly precisely) this past year, in an effort to understand what I really value and to be more mindful and aware of where I&amp;rsquo;m spending these limited resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the nondiscretionary chunks of my income go towards taxes, student loan payments, and rent (in descending order of relative amounts). &lt;em&gt;C&amp;rsquo;est la vie&lt;/em&gt;, insert grumbling here, etc etc. It is what it is. As an unmarried and child-free person, the rest I am more or less free to do with what I like, which is a lucky position to be in. Here is the breakdown of that discretionary spending in 2022&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 in review</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 14:55:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: if you have published a similar 2022 in review on your site, I would love to see it! You can email me a link at kwon(at)fastmail(dot)com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did 2022 go? All things told, it was&amp;hellip; a year. In reflecting on how to reflect on this past year (I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed, but I am an overthinker, particularly when it comes to writing things here), I had trouble relying on recall for notable events and accomplishments. As part of a separate personal exercise to work towards defining what my (aspirational) principles are, I realized that no matter what I &lt;em&gt;claim&lt;/em&gt; I value, the cold hard truth lies in where and how I spend my resources: time, money, and energy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
