<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lists on Kwon.nyc</title>
    <link>https://kwon.nyc/tags/lists/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lists on Kwon.nyc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 09:52:57 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kwon.nyc/tags/lists/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Seven sandwiches</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/seven-sandwiches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 09:52:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/seven-sandwiches/</guid>
      <description>I love sandwiches. Below are some of my favorites and why.
First, a few constraints I will impose to keep it to a reasonable number of sandwiches: these are limited to New York (not that I haven&amp;rsquo;t had amazing sandwiches elsewhere), sandwiches I&amp;rsquo;ve had at least 3 times, excluding burgers (are burgers sandwiches?), excluding falafel sandwiches (not that I don&amp;rsquo;t love them but I can&amp;rsquo;t pick a favorite spot and also then we get into wrap territory which is going to introduce too much scope creep), and excluding chain restaurants (not that I won&amp;rsquo;t crush a Subway or Potbelly sandwich if the mood strikes me).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comfort food</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/comfort-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 17:05:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/comfort-food/</guid>
      <description>One of the main reasons why I would find it hard to leave New York is that I have grown accustomed to having what feels like infinite food options and over the years have cultivated my list of good food spots in the city down to a tee.
&amp;ldquo;Good&amp;rdquo; is a super subjective designation, especially for food. It can also be a sensitive and sometimes classist thing to talk about good food, so I would start by saying that I do not consider myself a foodie (even though objectively speaking I do think about food a lot and talk about it a lot and probably definitely spend an embarrassingly disproportionate amount of my disposable income on food because I genuinely enjoy eating so much).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 in review, part 2</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 09:40:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022-part-2/</guid>
      <description>As promised, here&amp;rsquo;s the second part of my year in review.
To recap: I audited where I spent my time (loosely) and where I spent my money (incredibly precisely) this past year, in an effort to understand what I really value and to be more mindful and aware of where I&amp;rsquo;m spending these limited resources.
First, the nondiscretionary chunks of my income go towards taxes, student loan payments, and rent (in descending order of relative amounts).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 in review</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 14:55:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022/</guid>
      <description>Note: if you have published a similar 2022 in review on your site, I would love to see it! You can email me a link at kwon(at)fastmail(dot)com.
How did 2022 go? All things told, it was&amp;hellip; a year. In reflecting on how to reflect on this past year (I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed, but I am an overthinker, particularly when it comes to writing things here), I had trouble relying on recall for notable events and accomplishments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newyorkiversary</title>
      <link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/newyorkiversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 17:06:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/newyorkiversary/</guid>
      <description>June 2021 marks my eleventh year in New York City. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to be here this long. The Plan™ was never to stay in New York for this long. The Plan™ was to come here for five years to learn how to be a surgeon, then go back to Chicago and be a surgeon and live happily ever after.
When I was younger, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think that carefully about my future, which is kind of terrifying to think about now, how I made decisions about my life without really thinking about them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
