<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Photos on Kwon.nyc</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/photos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Photos on Kwon.nyc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 08:51:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/photos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spring tune-up &#43; ride</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/spring-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 08:51:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/spring-ride/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since transitioning to a more or less Monday-thru-Friday, 9-to-5 work week, I often feel my brain is pretty fried on Fridays (fried-days?), as well as a general depletion of energy for socializing, so for the last several years I have kept Friday evenings open for myself. I try to spend that time doing something chill, by myself, and mostly screen-free, and then I go to bed at a reasonable hour.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinatown breakfast</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/chinatown-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 07:50:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/chinatown-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we lived in Tribeca, I could walk to Chinatown for breakfast. In general I am a morning person who avoids crowds and noise where possible&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, so I especially enjoyed being in the usually crowded and noisy neighborhood when it was on the quieter side with mostly just the residents of the neighborhood out and about, getting ready to open shops and stands and whatnot. You can get a great breakfast—you can get great food at any meal or snacktime—which is too often classified as &amp;ldquo;cheap eats&amp;rdquo; just because the prices are generally very reasonable (which feels pretty reductive, and dismissive of the skill required to consistently make a perfect soup dumpling or pumpkin bun or hand-pulled noodles or what have you). The other day we made the long and arduous journey from Brooklyn&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to have breakfast at Big Wong which is one of my favorite spots because it feels like a diner and I love diners. We ordered the crispy roast pork, which felt decadent, especially for breakfast, along with a salted pork and preserved egg congee, rice rolls with shrimp, and a plate of greens. (I&amp;rsquo;m getting hungry thinking about it again.) I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure the meal fueled the rest of my day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liminal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/liminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 21:14:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/liminal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I walk around and do other things while brushing my teeth (which I know I&amp;rsquo;m probably not supposed to do but I do it anyway, like using Q-tips to clean my ears) and the other night I was winding down for the evening, brushing my teeth and zoning out while walking around the apartment and I noticed someone&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; had left the light on in my home office and it kinda looked like a liminal space:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdoors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/outdoors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 22:31:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/outdoors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent some time in the Bay Area this past week and did a vigorous hike (among other things). I was made to believe it would be more of a &amp;ldquo;nature walk&amp;rdquo; but this one, Mission Peak, had a steep grade and full exposure to the elements, and ended up being about 3.5 hours and close to 30,000 steps. I haven&amp;rsquo;t challenged myself physically like that in a long time so I was pleasantly surprised that I survived.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer ride</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/summer-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 08:51:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/summer-ride/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the good part of summer right now, the part where it&amp;rsquo;s warm and sunny and the days are long but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t gotten too humid out. I went on a nice bike ride yesterday morning along a route I used to take years ago when I first moved to Brooklyn that I haven&amp;rsquo;t done since. Truthfully I have not been riding my bike as much as I used to (and I used to ride it EVERYWHERE). I am constantly amazed by how quickly this city evolves. The thing that was once another thing is now a new thing. I also forget how different it is on foot versus cycling versus in a car versus a bus versus the subway.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hon. Ketanji Brown Jackson&#39;s husband&#39;s socks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/socks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 08:58:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/socks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I keep an eye on the news through peripheral vision mostly but I noticed something about the confirmation hearings of the honorable Ketanji Brown Jackson that required my focus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;full&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;socks-full.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Screenshot of a news image of a courtroom photo showing Hon. Ketanji Brown Jackson&amp;#39;s husband sitting with one leg crossed over the other. He is wearing a suit and a bright blue sock is visible under his pant leg.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Hon. Ketanji Brown Jackson&amp;rsquo;s husband&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 09:07:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the top priorities when moving to Brooklyn was to have more space, particularly to have dedicated workspace. In our previous apartment, my office was a corner of the bedroom, which I was grateful to have, but also over time resentful. I love my work and my job (probably a litle too much), but seeing my workspace as the  first thing upon waking and the last before sleep made it hard for my brain to rest. (It wasn&amp;rsquo;t nearly as draining as sleeping on a twin bed in a call room in the corner of a patient ward with my pager on my chest, though, like I used to have to do during my surgery training, which is always helpful to recall for perspective.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle storycle (bike story)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/bike-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 09:23:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/bike-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; I made a new page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://kwon.nyc/bike/&#34;&gt;kwon.nyc/bike&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January 2010 I was in my final year of medical school and had some rare free time for several weeks on a light rotation. My Local Bike Shop™ was offering classes on how to build a bike, so I enrolled and learned a lot about bike parts and bike maintenance. (Oddly enough, we didn&amp;rsquo;t actually build bikes.) Over the next few years I started building up a track bike, slowly amassing parts from my travels, getting the naked frame painted and framesaved, et cetera.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
