<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Neither Here nor There on Kwon.nyc</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/tags/neither-here-nor-there/</link><description>Recent content in Neither Here nor There on Kwon.nyc</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 08:51:52 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kwon.nyc/tags/neither-here-nor-there/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stubs</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/stubs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 08:51:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/stubs/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>An interesting blog post.&lt;/strong>
I liked &lt;a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/cities-need-more-trees/">this note about trees in Johannesburg&lt;/a> by Herman. In our last apartment, the bedroom faced a quiet tree-filled backyard despite the apartment itself being on a major two-way avenue, so I woke up to birds chirping and almost non-existent street noise, and a view of lush greenery. In our current apartment, the bedroom faces a brick wall and a one-way side street adjacent to a one-way main street, so now I have a classic New York wakeup call which is horns honking, garbage trucks rattling, pigeons cooing and flapping, and occasionally people walking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hon. Ketanji Brown Jackson's husband's socks</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/socks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 08:58:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/socks/</guid><description>&lt;p>I keep an eye on the news through peripheral vision mostly but I noticed something about the confirmation hearings of the honorable Ketanji Brown Jackson that required my focus:&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="full">
&lt;img loading="lazy" src="socks-full.png"
alt="Screenshot of a news image of a courtroom photo showing Hon. Ketanji Brown Jackson&amp;#39;s husband sitting with one leg crossed over the other. He is wearing a suit and a bright blue sock is visible under his pant leg."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Hon. Ketanji Brown Jackson&amp;rsquo;s husband&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Power moves</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/power-moves/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 11:28:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/power-moves/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yesterday one of my colleagues in a (virtual) meeting reportedly picked up a canister of coarse sea salt, announced &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m just snacking,&amp;rdquo; and proceeded to eat the salt, which confused and maybe frightened the other meeting attendees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It reminded me of the time I was rounding with my interns and medical students in the recovery room after scrubbing out of a long case and I was hungry so I pulled an apple out of my white coat pocket, ate most of it, noticed that there weren&amp;rsquo;t any trash cans close by, and so I ate the core and seeds as well and then deposited the stem in the breast pocket of my white coat to discard later.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>