<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Health on Kwon.nyc</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/tags/health/</link><description>Recent content in Health on Kwon.nyc</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 09:01:53 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kwon.nyc/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Eyeballs</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/eyeballs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 09:01:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/eyeballs/</guid><description>I recently got contact lenses, for the first time in 34 years, as someone who has required corrective eyewear since the age of 6.
I have attributed the decision mostly to my ongoing midlife/existential crisis — as a way to prove to myself that I&amp;rsquo;m NOT set in my ways and I CAN do new things — and for whatever reason I had increasingly been thinking that my eyeglasses are my whole personality and I was interested in experimenting with a different look.</description></item><item><title>Lunch break</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/lunch-break/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 08:08:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/lunch-break/</guid><description>I never had a regular &amp;ldquo;lunch break&amp;rdquo; until recently. Early in my career it was not by choice — in surgery training there&amp;rsquo;s really no such thing as a break, only a stolen minute or two here and there to pee or wolf down whatever food you can scrounge or nap in a chair if it&amp;rsquo;s the middle of the night and you&amp;rsquo;re on call. We did get a $5 meal coupon for the hospital cafeteria which could get you a cup of terrible coffee and a bagel drier than a bag of silica gel in the Sahara desert.</description></item><item><title>My lil' midlife crisis</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/my-lil-midlife-crisis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 13:49:35 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/my-lil-midlife-crisis/</guid><description>For the last several months I have been experiencing something, first in the background and now very much in the foreground, and that thing is what many people would describe as a midlife crisis, although it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel so much like a crisis mode and is in fact both exciting and exhausting, and fun and terrifying, and lots of other things.
I have a lot of mixed feelings about it, because I sort of thought I had already had my midlife crisis when I dramatically quit my career in my early 30s to TAKE A PRINCIPLED STAND and CHANGE THE WORLD and that from then on I would be sailing off into the sunset.</description></item><item><title>2022 in review</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 14:55:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022/</guid><description>Note: if you have published a similar 2022 in review on your site, I would love to see it! You can email me a link at kwon(at)fastmail(dot)com.
How did 2022 go? All things told, it was&amp;hellip; a year. In reflecting on how to reflect on this past year (I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed, but I am an overthinker, particularly when it comes to writing things here), I had trouble relying on recall for notable events and accomplishments.</description></item><item><title>Covid: the Sequel</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/covid-the-sequel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 12:21:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/covid-the-sequel/</guid><description>Well, Covid got me again. I’m recovering from a second bout after having had it in April 2020. That feels like a different era of fear and confusion—testing was nonexistent, we were running out of toilet paper and Tylenol, and the general guidance was to isolate but go to the emergency room if you were really sick but to call ahead and wear a mask and also if you were sick but not sick sick you should call your doctor (and you better know the difference between sick sick and sick and you better have a pulse oximeter at home, what do you mean you don’t have a pulse oximeter at home?</description></item><item><title>Early bird</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/early-bird/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 07:01:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/early-bird/</guid><description>I have been doing a Thing™ lately where I let the morning light wake me up instead of an alarm. Currently I am on an approximately two week streak of waking up at sunrise, and because the bedroom faces east, this means I have been waking up around 5:30 am. (Voluntarily!)
I wish I were one of those people who could function on 5 or 6 hours of sleep, but alas, somewhat embarrassingly I need a full 8 to 9 in order to really feel rested.</description></item></channel></rss>