<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal Reflection on Kwon.nyc</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/tags/personal-reflection/</link><description>Recent content in Personal Reflection on Kwon.nyc</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 18:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kwon.nyc/tags/personal-reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My name is</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/my-name-is/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 18:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/my-name-is/</guid><description>&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s in a name? Lots of things.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="primary-name">Primary name&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Most people call me Rachel. A certain subset of friends from a certain time in my life call me Kwon. I&amp;rsquo;ll respond to either.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="professional-name">Professional name&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>My coworkers call me Rachel. From 2010-2016, a lot of people called me Dr. Kwon. Infrequently these days, some people in certain contexts still try to call me Dr. Kwon, or ask me if I want to be called Dr., but most of the time I say &amp;ldquo;just call me Rachel.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lately</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/lately/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 22:03:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/lately/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a little less online lately, but not to worry, I have just been living my life :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Several weeks ago, I gave notice at work and left. Some people in my life were surprised, because it was a good job at a good company, I generally enjoyed it, I got to work with wonderful people, and I was paid money to do it. The younger version of me who hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet figured out a career direction would be curious (and more than a little skeptical) about why I would quit such an objectively good job.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Which self is this?</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/which-self-is-this/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 09:20:16 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/which-self-is-this/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last month &lt;a href="https://kayserifserif.place/">Katherine&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://sunny.garden/@kayserifserif/111523195687578771">called out&lt;/a> the tension inherent in a &amp;ldquo;personal&amp;rdquo; website which is that it is both public and personal, and one&amp;rsquo;s public (or professional) persona is often different from that of their personal life. &lt;a href="https://robinrendle.com/notes/i-am-a-poem-i-am-not-software/">Robin Rendle&lt;/a> riffed on the concept and said that it&amp;rsquo;s totally fine for personal websites to be messy or imperfect or weird (i.e., not necessarily how you&amp;rsquo;d want to present a &amp;ldquo;professional&amp;rdquo; front) and declared, in a pretty great and punchy/pithy statement, &amp;ldquo;You’re a poem and not software&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a href="https://manuelmoreale.com/the-personality-of-a-personal-website">Manu&lt;/a> also picked up the thread and brought up a good point which is that people are complex and are allowed to have multiple selves that they present in different ways (and one great thing about your website is that it&amp;rsquo;s yours and you can choose which self or selves to present, and how).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Things I don't have to do</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/things-i-dont-have-to-do/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 22:14:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/things-i-dont-have-to-do/</guid><description>&lt;p>I spent a lot of time and energy in my life worrying about things I felt like I &lt;em>had&lt;/em> to do for one reason or another. Either everyone else was doing the thing, or specific people were pressuring me to do the thing, or I never saw real examples or models of people who &lt;em>didn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em> do the thing, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At some point I started to realize that, if I really challenged myself, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to do some of the things I believed I had to in order to win at life (and I would include the idea of having to &amp;ldquo;win at life&amp;rdquo; on this list). I also couldn&amp;rsquo;t really blame anyone for making the decisions that I did because I felt I had to; no one was forcing me to do these things.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My lil' midlife crisis</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/my-lil-midlife-crisis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 13:49:35 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/my-lil-midlife-crisis/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the last several months I have been experiencing something, first in the background and now very much in the foreground, and that thing is what many people would describe as a midlife crisis, although it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel so much like a crisis mode and is in fact both exciting and exhausting, and fun and terrifying, and lots of other things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a lot of mixed feelings about it, because I sort of thought I had already had my midlife crisis when I dramatically quit my career in my early 30s to TAKE A PRINCIPLED STAND and CHANGE THE WORLD and that from then on I would be sailing off into the sunset.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Optimize</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/optimize/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 23:06:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/optimize/</guid><description>&lt;p>After I quit medicine and went corporate (as corporate as tech startups can be, which I guess depends on your vantage point; for me it was and is extremely corporate coming from doctoring), I got really into it and became particularly fascinated to learn how business leaders operate and spend their time (at work and in life) in order to be the most efficient and effective they can be. I guess a lot of people who came up in corporate work (and maybe the culture at large which is often dictated by creatives who may pooh-pooh the corporate life) think MASSIVE EYEROLL when they hear what the latest tech bro thinkboi has to say about optimizing their life and their time, but I actually found it pretty refreshing that in business a spade is called a spade and that spade is a dollar and nobody pretends that we aren&amp;rsquo;t trying to make money. Whereas when I was a doctor it was like someone was telling me out of one side of their mouth that I should take care of patients and money isn&amp;rsquo;t important but out of the other side they were whispering (but really shouting) that the patient doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, just make money for the hospital.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2022 in review, part 2</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 09:40:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>As &lt;a href="https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022/">promised&lt;/a>, here&amp;rsquo;s the second part of my year in review.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To recap: I audited where I spent my time (loosely) and where I spent my money (incredibly precisely) this past year, in an effort to understand what I really value and to be more mindful and aware of where I&amp;rsquo;m spending these limited resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, the nondiscretionary chunks of my income go towards taxes, student loan payments, and rent (in descending order of relative amounts). &lt;em>C&amp;rsquo;est la vie&lt;/em>, insert grumbling here, etc etc. It is what it is. As an unmarried and child-free person, the rest I am more or less free to do with what I like, which is a lucky position to be in. Here is the breakdown of that discretionary spending in 2022&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2022 in review</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 14:55:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Note: if you have published a similar 2022 in review on your site, I would love to see it! You can email me a link at kwon(at)fastmail(dot)com.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How did 2022 go? All things told, it was&amp;hellip; a year. In reflecting on how to reflect on this past year (I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed, but I am an overthinker, particularly when it comes to writing things here), I had trouble relying on recall for notable events and accomplishments. As part of a separate personal exercise to work towards defining what my (aspirational) principles are, I realized that no matter what I &lt;em>claim&lt;/em> I value, the cold hard truth lies in where and how I spend my resources: time, money, and energy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Flashback</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/flashback/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 06:51:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/flashback/</guid><description>&lt;p>This past weekend I met up with a few of my former colleagues from residency for dinner and drinks. It felt a little bit like a meetup with high school friends might feel, if you spent high school removing gallbladders and incising and draining abscesses. (Maybe you did. I don&amp;rsquo;t know your life.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having a chance to confront and reflect on my former self in a controlled environment—in this case, a contemporary Mexican restaurant—was not a bad exercise. Part of me was hesitant, as my general feeling towards that time in my life is &amp;ldquo;thank you, universe, for the opportunity to learn about the world and myself, but also, don&amp;rsquo;t ever put me there again.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Distracted</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/distracted/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 09:30:24 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/distracted/</guid><description>&lt;p>RIP to my attention span.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The world seems to be opening back up now that we are no longer surging (or are just between surges?), but I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say that I feel normal again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lack of focus has been one of the most pronounced negative effects. For example, I sat down with a cup of coffee and opened up a text editor to write this note about an hour ago and have since abandoned the window no fewer than seven times (see &lt;a href="#appendix">Appendix&lt;/a>).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Newyorkiversary</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/newyorkiversary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 17:06:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/newyorkiversary/</guid><description>&lt;p>June 2021 marks my eleventh year in New York City. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to be here this long. The Plan™ was never to stay in New York for this long. The Plan™ was to come here for five years to learn how to be a surgeon, then go back to Chicago and be a surgeon and live happily ever after.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I was younger, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think that carefully about my future, which is kind of terrifying to think about now, how I made decisions about my life without really thinking about them. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to be kinder to my younger self and recognize that she was doing the best she could with what she had, even if she didn&amp;rsquo;t make the decisions that my present self would make, with the benefit of hindsight.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Goodbye and hello</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/why-i-quit-medicine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 22:02:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/why-i-quit-medicine/</guid><description>&lt;p>As some of you have heard, I recently resigned from surgical residency, and am leaving clinical medicine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ten years ago, I decided to be a doctor. It was a decision that made perfect sense at the time: I wanted to help people who were suffering, and I was fortunate to have the ability and resources to gain entry into medical school. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure which specialty would be my calling, but shortly after starting my clinical rotations I fell in love with surgery. I loved seeing and evaluating patients who had a very clear and usually dramatic surgical problem that I knew could be solved by an operation, by putting hands on the patient and potentially curing them of whatever it was that was ailing them.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>