<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thoughts on Kwon.nyc</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/tags/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in Thoughts on Kwon.nyc</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 18:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kwon.nyc/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My name is</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/my-name-is/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 18:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/my-name-is/</guid><description>&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s in a name? Lots of things.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="primary-name">Primary name&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Most people call me Rachel. A certain subset of friends from a certain time in my life call me Kwon. I&amp;rsquo;ll respond to either.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="professional-name">Professional name&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>My coworkers call me Rachel. From 2010-2016, a lot of people called me Dr. Kwon. Infrequently these days, some people in certain contexts still try to call me Dr. Kwon, or ask me if I want to be called Dr., but most of the time I say &amp;ldquo;just call me Rachel.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wintering better</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/wintering-better/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:55:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/wintering-better/</guid><description>&lt;p>Everyone loves summer. If you have to name a favorite season (which you absolutely don&amp;rsquo;t!! Who says you do?), summer is a non-controversial option. Bright sun, long days, beach time, et cetera. And spring is a close runner-up, with its warmer weather, greenery and flowers, and of course the anticipation of summer. If you want to be alternative and edgy (i.e., me in early adulthood lol), you&amp;rsquo;d cite fall (or ðŸ‚&lt;em>autumn&lt;/em>ðŸ‚, to put some extra sauce on it) as your favorite season, for its foliage, cider, pumpkin patches, sweater weather.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Radicalized by a soap dispenser</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/radicalized-by-a-soap-dispenser/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 09:01:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/radicalized-by-a-soap-dispenser/</guid><description>&lt;p>I get frustrated when things don&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Increasingly I have been getting especially frustrated when things &lt;strong>that are fancy&lt;/strong> don&amp;rsquo;t work, because I feel bamboozled.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other day, I went to wash my hands in the bathroom at work, and the automated soap dispenser/foamer didn&amp;rsquo;t work. I was awkwardly placing and retracting my hands under the sensor repeatedly like &lt;em>please sir&amp;hellip; just a bit of soap to wash my bathroom hands&lt;/em>&amp;hellip; and nothing. No soap for you. I looked a little more closely and saw a ðŸª« low battery icon on a small LED indicator at the base of the dispenser. I sighed and moved over to the next dispenser, which did work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>In-between moments</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/in-between-moments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 08:35:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/in-between-moments/</guid><description>&lt;p>In addition to my &lt;a href="https://kwon.nyc/notes/distracted/">attention span&lt;/a>, another pandemic-related loss not immediately obvious to me (probably because I was too worried about all the other losses, like the human lives, and the general erosion of mental health, and the ability to pretend that the institutions holding up our society would be able to take care of our most vulnerable), which I am only now realizing, has been the in-between moments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 30 minutes between leaving work and meeting up with a friend for drinks is an in-between moment. The subway commute that was too crowded to even think so I&amp;rsquo;d have to mentally check out is an in-between moment. The time spent standing on line at the post office during a quick lunch break is an in-between moment.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>