<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Money on Kwon.nyc</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/tags/money/</link><description>Recent content in Money on Kwon.nyc</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 23:06:33 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kwon.nyc/tags/money/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Optimize</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/optimize/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 23:06:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/optimize/</guid><description>After I quit medicine and went corporate (as corporate as tech startups can be, which I guess depends on your vantage point; for me it was and is extremely corporate coming from doctoring), I got really into it and became particularly fascinated to learn how business leaders operate and spend their time (at work and in life) in order to be the most efficient and effective they can be. I guess a lot of people who came up in corporate work (and maybe the culture at large which is often dictated by creatives who may pooh-pooh the corporate life) think MASSIVE EYEROLL when they hear what the latest tech bro thinkboi has to say about optimizing their life and their time, but I actually found it pretty refreshing that in business a spade is called a spade and that spade is a dollar and nobody pretends that we aren&amp;rsquo;t trying to make money.</description></item><item><title>2022 in review, part 2</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 09:40:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/2022-part-2/</guid><description>As promised, here&amp;rsquo;s the second part of my year in review.
To recap: I audited where I spent my time (loosely) and where I spent my money (incredibly precisely) this past year, in an effort to understand what I really value and to be more mindful and aware of where I&amp;rsquo;m spending these limited resources.
First, the nondiscretionary chunks of my income go towards taxes, student loan payments, and rent (in descending order of relative amounts).</description></item></channel></rss>