<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>New York City on Kwon.nyc</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/tags/new-york-city/</link><description>Recent content in New York City on Kwon.nyc</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 08:51:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kwon.nyc/tags/new-york-city/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spring tune-up + ride</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/spring-ride/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 08:51:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/spring-ride/</guid><description>Since transitioning to a more or less Monday-thru-Friday, 9-to-5 work week, I often feel my brain is pretty fried on Fridays (fried-days?), as well as a general depletion of energy for socializing, so for the last several years I have kept Friday evenings open for myself. I try to spend that time doing something chill, by myself, and mostly screen-free, and then I go to bed at a reasonable hour.</description></item><item><title>Seven sandwiches</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/seven-sandwiches/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 09:52:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/seven-sandwiches/</guid><description>I love sandwiches. Below are some of my favorites and why.
First, a few constraints I will impose to keep it to a reasonable number of sandwiches: these are limited to New York (not that I haven&amp;rsquo;t had amazing sandwiches elsewhere), sandwiches I&amp;rsquo;ve had at least 3 times, excluding burgers (are burgers sandwiches?), excluding falafel sandwiches (not that I don&amp;rsquo;t love them but I can&amp;rsquo;t pick a favorite spot and also then we get into wrap territory which is going to introduce too much scope creep), and excluding chain restaurants (not that I won&amp;rsquo;t crush a Subway or Potbelly sandwich if the mood strikes me).</description></item><item><title>Comfort food</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/comfort-food/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 17:05:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/comfort-food/</guid><description>One of the main reasons why I would find it hard to leave New York is that I have grown accustomed to having what feels like infinite food options and over the years have cultivated my list of good food spots in the city down to a tee.
&amp;ldquo;Good&amp;rdquo; is a super subjective designation, especially for food. It can also be a sensitive and sometimes classist thing to talk about good food, so I would start by saying that I do not consider myself a foodie (even though objectively speaking I do think about food a lot and talk about it a lot and probably definitely spend an embarrassingly disproportionate amount of my disposable income on food because I genuinely enjoy eating so much).</description></item><item><title>In-between moments</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/in-between-moments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 08:35:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/in-between-moments/</guid><description>In addition to my attention span, another pandemic-related loss not immediately obvious to me (probably because I was too worried about all the other losses, like the human lives, and the general erosion of mental health, and the ability to pretend that the institutions holding up our society would be able to take care of our most vulnerable), which I am only now realizing, has been the in-between moments.
The 30 minutes between leaving work and meeting up with a friend for drinks is an in-between moment.</description></item><item><title>Chinatown breakfast</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/chinatown-breakfast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 07:50:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/chinatown-breakfast/</guid><description>When we lived in Tribeca, I could walk to Chinatown for breakfast. In general I am a morning person who avoids crowds and noise where possible1, so I especially enjoyed being in the usually crowded and noisy neighborhood when it was on the quieter side with mostly just the residents of the neighborhood out and about, getting ready to open shops and stands and whatnot. You can get a great breakfast—you can get great food at any meal or snacktime—which is too often classified as &amp;ldquo;cheap eats&amp;rdquo; just because the prices are generally very reasonable (which feels pretty reductive, and dismissive of the skill required to consistently make a perfect soup dumpling or pumpkin bun or hand-pulled noodles or what have you).</description></item><item><title>Language</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 08:30:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/language/</guid><description>Several years ago, the Metropolitan Transit Authority of New York City made a major change that affected every subway and bus ride overnight, but not many people noticed.
What happened? Announcers were trained to avoid using gendered language, such as “Ladies and gentlemen,” and instead use greetings like “Attention passengers” or “Good morning everyone” prior to making an announcement.
Okay, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t earth-shattering. But I thought it was a great example of a small, easy, tangible way to be more inclusive, without being overly fussy or political about it.</description></item><item><title>Tuesday</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/tuesday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 07:40:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/tuesday/</guid><description>The cadence of life is a little different now that I live in Brooklyn and work from home. In my 12 years in New York City, I have:
lived in Brooklyn and worked in Brooklyn lived in Brooklyn and worked in Manhattan (the worst overall) lived in Manhattan and worked in Manhattan lived in Manhattan and worked from home lived in Brooklyn and worked from home and the one that feels most like not working at all is living in Brooklyn and working from home.</description></item><item><title>Newyorkiversary</title><link>https://kwon.nyc/notes/newyorkiversary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 17:06:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kwon.nyc/notes/newyorkiversary/</guid><description>June 2021 marks my eleventh year in New York City. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to be here this long. The Plan™ was never to stay in New York for this long. The Plan™ was to come here for five years to learn how to be a surgeon, then go back to Chicago and be a surgeon and live happily ever after.
When I was younger, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think that carefully about my future, which is kind of terrifying to think about now, how I made decisions about my life without really thinking about them.</description></item></channel></rss>