<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Midlife on Kwon.nyc</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/midlife/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Midlife on Kwon.nyc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 22:14:03 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/midlife/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Things I don&#39;t have to do</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/things-i-dont-have-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 22:14:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/things-i-dont-have-to-do/</guid>
      <description>I spent a lot of time and energy in my life worrying about things I felt like I had to do for one reason or another. Either everyone else was doing the thing, or specific people were pressuring me to do the thing, or I never saw real examples or models of people who didn&amp;rsquo;t do the thing, etc.
At some point I started to realize that, if I really challenged myself, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to do some of the things I believed I had to in order to win at life (and I would include the idea of having to &amp;ldquo;win at life&amp;rdquo; on this list).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My lil&#39; midlife crisis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/my-lil-midlife-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 13:49:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/my-lil-midlife-crisis/</guid>
      <description>For the last several months I have been experiencing something, first in the background and now very much in the foreground, and that thing is what many people would describe as a midlife crisis, although it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel so much like a crisis mode and is in fact both exciting and exhausting, and fun and terrifying, and lots of other things.
I have a lot of mixed feelings about it, because I sort of thought I had already had my midlife crisis when I dramatically quit my career in my early 30s to TAKE A PRINCIPLED STAND and CHANGE THE WORLD and that from then on I would be sailing off into the sunset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
