<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Habits on Kwon.nyc</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/habits/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Habits on Kwon.nyc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 14:55:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/habits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2022 in review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 14:55:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: if you have published a similar 2022 in review on your site, I would love to see it! You can email me a link at kwon(at)fastmail(dot)com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did 2022 go? All things told, it was&amp;hellip; a year. In reflecting on how to reflect on this past year (I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed, but I am an overthinker, particularly when it comes to writing things here), I had trouble relying on recall for notable events and accomplishments. As part of a separate personal exercise to work towards defining what my (aspirational) principles are, I realized that no matter what I &lt;em&gt;claim&lt;/em&gt; I value, the cold hard truth lies in where and how I spend my resources: time, money, and energy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early bird</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/early-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 07:01:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/early-bird/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been doing a Thing™ lately where I let the morning light wake me up instead of an alarm. Currently I am on an approximately two week streak of waking up at sunrise, and because the bedroom faces east, this means I have been waking up around 5:30 am. (Voluntarily!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I were one of those people who could function on 5 or 6 hours of sleep, but alas, somewhat embarrassingly I need a full 8 to 9 in order to really feel rested. After having horrible sleep hygiene during my surgery training and to some degree during medical school, I have since prioritized sleep hygiene pretty highly and I guess this is the natural evolution to my final form: a 38 year old woman who starts winding down for the night at 8:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
